Shuhel Ahmed

Sylhet, Bangladesh Email: shuhel@ymail.com

Github: http://github.com/ahmedshuhel

Cell/Mobile: +8801834548051

Summary

- Full-stack software engineer offering 5+ years of experience working in a variety of environments with a breadth of programs and technologies.
- Extensive experience in Agile Development, Test-Driven Development, Domain-Driven Design, Object-Oriented Design, and Service Oriented Architecture.
- Experience in building high traffic web applications and APIs, large-scale data processing systems on the AWS Platform.
- Proven track records of providing technical leadership.

Key Areas of Expertise

REST, Microservice, Design Patterns, Enterprise Applications, Agile, Databases (SQL/NoSQL), .NET, JavaScript, Test-driven development (TDD/BDD), SPA, Domain Driven Design, CQRS, Event Sourcing, MVVM, MVP, MVC, User Experience.

Programming Language

Proficient: Python, JavaScript, C#, Typescript Familiar with: Java, C/C++, Rust, Go, Scala, F#

Technology Stack

Client Side: JavaScript, React, AngularJS, Aurelia, DurandalJS, Winforms. Familiar with Angular 2,

Xemarin/Xemarin Forms, React Native, Cordova

Server Side: Python, Flask, Django, C#/.NET, ASP.NET MVC, Web API, Node, ExpressJS. Familiar with Koa,

micro, Nancy.

Database: MS SQL Server, MySQL, MongoDB. Familiar with Redshift, PostgreSQL and Oracle

Experience

2016-Present Tech Lead (Engineering Manager) NewsCred Inc., Dhaka, Bangladesh

- Led an effort in re-implementing and improving the core product (Task and Workflow) in Content Marketing Platform (CMP) from AngularJS to ReactJS.
- Developed "NewsCred for Sales", an Account based Content Marketing (ABCM) system, that helps the Sales rep to engage with Leads and Opportunities via stories, articles, infographics and then track and measure Account health based on interactions.
- Developed an internal tool for tracking original content budgets, which improves the productivity of the Editorial team by more than 70%.
- Developed tools to measure Content Marketing maturity of customers (CMMI), improving efficiency of deployment and program adoption.
- Developed an automated data pipeline which aggregates data from various sources to AWS Redshift and created data visualization to understand and analyze the trends, usage patterns, etc.
- Automated infrastructure management using Ansible, and built CI/CD pipelines using Jenkins for the organization.
- Implemented multi-factor authentication in OAuth2/OpenId Connect based single sign-on server to comply with security requirements of enterprise customers.
- Decomposed an existing monolithic system into a Microservice architecture to achieve stability and scalability.
- Lead and guide engineering teams to design scalable systems and cooperate with the Product Manager to plan and schedule.
- Managing 4 software engineers as an engineering manager and assisting them to grow in the organization.

- Led the development of two ERP solutions: One system manages 820 units (and 250000 people) located across the country and the other one is in the Hospital domain deployed to four mid size Hospitals at the time. Key modules includes: HRM, Training & Result Processing, Stock & Inventory, Ration Management, POL Management, OPD, IPD, Nursing Station, Admission, Emergency, OT, Day Care Center, Diagnostic Center, Follow Up and Prescription, Accounting, Billing and Payroll.
- Implemented a visual query builder and a search platform that operates on a highly de-normalized data repository containing a huge volume of data.
- Implemented single sign-on server using OpenID Connect based authentication/authorization server framework, IdentityServer for the ERPs.
- Wrote user stories, use cases and created high fidelity mock-ups using AxureRP collaborating with domain experts to analyze requirements and UX which led to high quality software, increased user satisfaction and adoption rate.
- Decomposed system into smaller services adhering Microservice architecture. Implemented messaging patterns such as Publish/Subscribe, Request/Response using RabbitMQ, EasyNetQ, Windows Service with Topshelf achieving higher scalability.
- Wrote Scaffolders in PowerShell and a helper framework that cut down the development time from 6/7 days to 5/6 hours for developers.
- Led a team of 5 engineers and provided training on TDD/BDD, CI/CD and frameworks like AngularJS, Angular Material, ASP.NET MVC, etc.

2010-2012 Independent Contractor(Remote) Xerasoft Ltd, Surrey, UK

- Designed and developed a restaurant management system (RMS) and online order processing system that is being used by over 150 restaurants in the UK. Integrated with Printer, Caller Id, Customer Display using UnifiedPOS/POS.NET.
- Created a Model-View-Controller (MVC) framework in C#/WinForms to achieve SPA like experience and used in the RMS application.
- Designed and developed a tablet-based companion application for Waiting staffs to take dine-in orders.

2008-2010

Software Engineer

C&E Software Solutions Ltd., Sylhet, Bangladesh

- Developed C# and WinForms applications that record sales, monitor inventory, keep customer ledger, and bill customer for a drinking water plant and distribution company.
- Designed and Developed a utility billing software for supermarket/shopping centers using C#, .NET, and WinForms.

Education

Metropolitan University – Sylhet, Bangladesh, 2008 B.Sc., Computer Science and Engineering

Open Source

- Core team member of <u>Aurelia Framework (https://aurelia.io/)</u>
- Contributed to: <u>Aurelia Bundler (https://github.com/aurelia/bundler)</u>, <u>Aurelia CLI (https://github.com/aurelia/cli)</u>, <u>Aurelia (https://github.com/aurelia/framework)</u>, <u>JSPM (https://github.com/jspm/jspm-cli)</u>, SystemJS Builder, Humanizer, Fluent Migrator, etc.

Languages

- English (Fluent)
- Bangla (Native)